Gibson Murimi Muriuki

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- ≥ gibsonmurimi4@gmail.com
- 0758519193
- Nairobi, Kenya
- in linkedin.com/in/muriuki-gibson-2b5719229
- https://github.com/Gabu-Rayon

Profile

I am a passionate software engineer with 1+ year of experience, excited to bring my expertise and abilities to your organization. With my proven technical competencies, strong problem-solving skills, and experience in delivering successful software solutions, I believe I can make a valuable contribution to your team. In addition to my technical skills, I am a good communicator, excellent team player, reliable timekeeper, and flexible in my approach to work. I am always eager to learn and grow as a professional, and I am committed to staying up to date with the latest industry trends and technologies. I am excited about the opportunity to join your team and contribute to the success of your organization.

Education

Bachelors of Science in Software

Development, KCA University.

May 2019 – December 2023 | Nairobi, Kenya

Professional Experience

Junior TIMS/eTIMS developer, Your Apps Ltd ☐ May 2024 – present | Nairobi, Kenya

- Design, develop, test, and deploy software applications using modern programming languages and frameworks.
- Work closely with product managers, designers, and other engineers to understand requirements and deliver solutions that align with business goals.
- Write clean, maintainable, and efficient code. Conduct code reviews and contribute to improving coding standards and best practices.
- Identify, debug, and resolve software defects and performance issues.
- Stay updated with the latest industry trends, technologies, and best practices. Propose and implement improvements to enhance software quality and development processes.
- Create and maintain technical documentation in the prescribed format in support of development processes and knowledge sharing

Intership, Meru University of Science and Technology.

Meru University of Science and Technology ☑ January 2023 – April 2023 | Meru, Kenya

- Collaborated with ICT & IT team to achieve University objectives in the field of ERP System Administration and Network administration
- Trained Users on System's functionality and promoted better understanding of the application suite
- Provided Technical support for university ERP system Infrastructure
- Managed and maintained Linux servers for application deployment and hosting
- Performed system administration tasks on Linux servers, including installation, configuration, troubleshooting, resolving any related hardware, software and user access requirements problems
- Implement server monitoring and optimization strategies to ensure optimal performance and uptime
- Worked with ICT & IT team to design and implement new features in the university System
- Successfully completed all tasks on time and within deadline
- Implemented security and scalability features in all University applications
- Received positive feedback from team members and stakeholders

Software Developer Freelancer,

NelsonelTech Solutions Ltd ☑

June 2022 – December 2022 | Nairobi, Kenya

- Collaborated with a multidisciplinary team to design, develop, and maintain software applications aligned with business requirements.
- Implemented efficient and scalable solutions using JavaScript ESMA6, leveraging frameworks such as React.
- Participated in the full software development lifecycle, including requirement gathering, coding, testing, and deployment.
- Conducted rigorous testing and debugging to identify and resolve software defects, ensuring high-quality deliverables as per the client requirements.
- Actively researched and recommended new tools, technologies, and development practices to improve productivity and innovation.
- Engaged in regular communication with crossfunctional teams, promoting collaboration and ensuring project goals were met.
- Demonstrated strong problem-solving skills, effectively troubleshooting complex technical issues.
- Stayed updated with industry trends and emerging technologies to drive continuous improvement.

Skills

Web Development	• •	•	
Mobile Development	• •		
Web Design	• •	•	
Databases Sql and Nosql	• •	• •	